<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tour de Niu</title>
        <link>https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Tour de Niu</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <managingEditor>tourdeniu@vonneudeck.com (Nicolai von Neudeck)</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>tourdeniu@vonneudeck.com (Nicolai von Neudeck)</webMaster>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Scooter</title>
        <link>https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>tourdeniu@vonneudeck.com (Nicolai von Neudeck)</author>
        <guid>https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/niu_seite.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Scooter" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After I made the decision to go on vacation it was time to buy a scooter. I wanted something low maintenance and reasonably modern, possibly with storage space under the seat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a long time I followed the developments around the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etergo.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AppScooter&lt;/a&gt;. I like the monocoque approach, the flexible triple battery approach and the gigantic trunc. But since its producer Etergo BV has been acquired by Ola Electric Mobility Pvt Ltd nothing has been heard of them. Hopefully they will be produced some day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new model from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://unumotors.com/de/product&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;unu&lt;/a&gt; with a large storage and a pretty sleek design seems also nice. But it has very long delivery times of more than 20 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third nicest option seemed to be the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.niu.com/en/n-series/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Niu N series&lt;/a&gt;. Not as elegant, a much smaller storage space and the technical approaches generally are far less sophisticated. But a decent scooter I can drive now is better for my vacation than a maybe never available genius concept or an order delivered half a year later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I oggled les petites annonces and found an attractive offer near the French/German/Luxembourgish border. A metallic red 2017 Niu N1S civic for 1350€. While talking with the sellers to negotiate and arrange everything, I found out that they had used a second battery with a rather simple Y-cable. I inquired about the second battery and the cable and they sold me all of it for 1950€. A good price considering that with electrical scooters one pays the &amp;ldquo;gasoline&amp;rdquo; in advance when buying the battery as the electricity costs are negligible with &amp;lt;3kWh/100km. After some back and forth about the needed papers for insurance I took a big leap of trust and wired them the money. Believe me that I  got a little nervous, but I decided to have faith in humanity. Registering the insurance turned out to be very easy. Now all I needed to do is buy all the accessories and take the train to the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my luggage, I ordered a rack with a blotched paint job from a less than stellar seller, whom I in hindsight suspect of comitting tax fraud. I had some trouble with him. In the end it all went well but in between he caused a lot of stress. The seller is active on ebay, ebay Kleinanzeigen and with his local shop in Southern Germany. Later I discovered that others had trouble with him as well. If you are in for a Niu scooter rack, feel free to write me, so I can warn you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the rack I put the only top case I could find that was neither prohibitively expensive nor terribly ugly. The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.louis.ie/artikel/top-box-eyecase-black-32-litres/10024090&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;eyecase L32&lt;/a&gt; by niemann und frey. It is pretty good, especially for the money, and the elegant locking mechanism brought me a lot of joy. I decided to put all the hard to replace things that needed to stay dry in there. Mostly my camping gear and toiletries. My most valuable belongings went into a small backpack I could carry with me at all times and the rest (clothes and an extension cable) I put in a smaller blue IKEA bag which I strapped on with the most genius invention of all time: an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://shop.zweirad-stadler.de/Motorrad-Bekleidung/Sonstiges/Warnwesten-Safety-Artikel/Roemer-Gepaecknetz-schwarz.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;elastic luggage net&lt;/a&gt;. Get yourself one, if you go on a ride. Nothing is as flexible, practical and useful. The last important thing besides a reflective security west for foggy nights is a bycicle lock. You need it also to lock the scooter in insecure areas but most importantly to lock the helmet when you are visiting something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/niu_luggage.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;1130x1764&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/niu_luggage_huae7a21f494b04d29858fcf0c7835661a_1437145_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/niu_luggage_huae7a21f494b04d29858fcf0c7835661a_1437145_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-scooter/niu_luggage.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1130&#34; height=&#34;1764&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;My Niu with all the luggage and the helmet locked to the rack&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;My Niu with all the luggage and the helmet locked to the rack&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding said helmet was a drama. I have a very long but not very wide head and get headaches easily. I went to almost all the different motor cycle accessory stores in Berlin and spent several days trying on helmets for many hours. In the end I found something that fit me on the last day before departure. The best salesperson of all those people was René (Hoffentlich schreibe ich deinen Namen richtig, vielen Dank nochmal für alles 😊) from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.louis.de/service/filialen/louis-berlin-lichtenberg/70&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Louis Store in Lichtenberg&lt;/a&gt; nearby the Đồng Xuân Center. He truely understood what I wanted to do and helped me so much. He deserves praise and a raise!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Idea</title>
        <link>https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>tourdeniu@vonneudeck.com (Nicolai von Neudeck)</author>
        <guid>https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/vineyard.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Idea" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;My family owns a vacation house in Southern France. In a cute little village named &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moux&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Moux&lt;/a&gt; with narrow roads and old houses. The area is rural, full of vinyards and has a typical Mediterranean climate: Plenty of sun and almost no frost.&lt;br&gt;
The landscape is beautiful, right between the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massif_central&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Massif Central&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pyrenees&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pyrenees&lt;/a&gt;. Traces of roman civilisation, wild gorges, old bridges, medieval buildings from modest castles to Cathar fortresses on the most remote mountain tops.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/villerouge.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;2601x1386&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/villerouge_hue14b4fa8192b7b45b1ae4aeb465266cc_2690386_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/villerouge_hue14b4fa8192b7b45b1ae4aeb465266cc_2690386_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/villerouge.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2601&#34; height=&#34;1386&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;Castle of Villerouge&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Castle of Villerouge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/gorge.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;2545x1217&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/gorge_huc758002f9a77be89ee1a71b9d6162a91_2121282_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/gorge_huc758002f9a77be89ee1a71b9d6162a91_2121282_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/gorge.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2545&#34; height=&#34;1217&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;One of many gorges&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;One of many gorges&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the French local train system is not what it used to be. The town technically has a train station and the tracks are used daily by trains between larger cities. But as far as I can tell it has been decades since the last train stopped here. And while the région Occitanie is trying to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.laregion.fr/Objectif-100-000-passagers-par-jour-dans-les-trains-d-Occitanie&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;revive its local train network&lt;/a&gt;, right now the public transport consists of a bus that rides three times a day. Hence one needs a car there. But I don’t own one, live 1600 km away and take the train for travels within Europe anyway. A car just for vacation does not make sense and renting them is expensive. Also I swore to myself a few years ago that I will never again buy a combustion engine. A car is ruled out. But a scooter would do the job. An electrical one. Used, so it isn’t too expensive. A 45 km/h slow one, which I don’t have to bring to technical controls in Germany and which can just stay in the South.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/kiefern.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;2535x1548&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/kiefern_hu29327ca044953717ac45433d0c485812_2955688_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/kiefern_hu29327ca044953717ac45433d0c485812_2955688_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/kiefern.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2535&#34; height=&#34;1548&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;Pines are dominant, cypresses and evergreen oaks apear too&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Pines are dominant, cypresses and evergreen oaks apear too&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/village.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;1548x2078&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/village_hud8a516ab6aa77fc1b364589a7b7d33aa_2070763_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/village_hud8a516ab6aa77fc1b364589a7b7d33aa_2070763_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/village.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1548&#34; height=&#34;2078&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;Remnants of the Castle of Moux&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Remnants of the Castle of Moux&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence the idea ripened to buy a scooter and drive it to Southern France. But electrical scooters can’t run too long distances on one charge and at 45 km/h Vmax one is not that fast anyway. So what! &lt;em&gt;The journey is the destination&lt;/em&gt; and after being caught in my small apartment during the first wave of COVID-19 I could really use some feeling of freedom and space! I’d take a tent and lodge mostly on camping municipal. A minimalist, silent, uninvasive, environmentally friendly, individualistic, slow vacation with fresh air and a lot to discover to the left and right!
&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/church.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;1366x2654&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/church_hu7835a6bacff20875c2b7f45037ea22e1_2538125_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/church_hu7835a6bacff20875c2b7f45037ea22e1_2538125_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/church.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1366&#34; height=&#34;2654&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;The fortified church. Property of Moux, not the Catholic church&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;The fortified church. Property of Moux, not the Catholic church&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/grave.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;1406x1974&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/grave_hu621635497e74f1935dff6f134524c3f1_2075549_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/grave_hu621635497e74f1935dff6f134524c3f1_2075549_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://tourdeniu.vonneudeck.com/p/the-plan/grave.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1406&#34; height=&#34;1974&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;Grave of the poet Henry Bataille from Moux, with a copy of the statue Transi by René de Chalon&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
		&lt;figcaption&gt;Grave of the poet Henry Bataille from Moux, with a copy of the statue Transi by René de Chalon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
